ILGWU International Relations Department publications 5780/062 PUBS
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU International Relations Department publications
1919-2000
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union
5780/062 PUBS
13 cubic feet
13 linear ft.
Publications (documents).
Consists of publications either created or collected by the International Relations Department of the ILGWU.
6796102
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, June 06, 2012
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 11, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was once one of the largest labor unions in the United States founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States. It was one of the first U.S. Unions to have a membership consisting of mostly females, and it played a key role in the labor history of the 1920s and 1930s. The union is generally referred to as the "ILGWU" or the "ILG". The ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, and political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. The ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union in 1995 to form the Union of Needle trades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). UNITE merged with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) in 2004 to create a new union known as UNITE HERE. The two unions that formed UNITE in 1995 represented only 250,000 workers between them, down from the ILGWU's peak membership of 450,000 in 1969.
Biographical / Historical
The International Relations Department of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU) was concerned primarily with outreach to foreign and international labor organizations, working conditions in foreign countries, and international organizing activities. The department worked closely with international relations units of national and international labor confederations, such as the Free Trade Union Committee (FTUC) and the International Confederation of Free Trade Unions (ICFTU).
For more information about the ILGWU's involvement in international affairs, please visit:
http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/ILGWU/collectionGuides/internationalAffairs.html
Scope and Contents
The International Relations Department records (5780/062) consist chiefly of the correspondence of its director, Henoch Mendlesund, during his tenure from 1968-1980, and Michele Briones. The collection also includes articles, reports, conference materials, photographs, and other items. The materials in this collection have an emphasis on labor issues in the developing world. There is correspondence with leaders of clothing and textile workers' unions in India, Japan, Turkey, Kenya, Latin America, Namibia, South Korea, among other countries. Other items concern conventions and conferences of the ILGWU that emphasized international issues, visits from foreign union leaders to the ILGWU, and visits of ILGWU leaders to foreign countries. There are also some materials about garment workers' unions in Western Europe. Topics addressed include working conditions, human rights, economic, political, and social conditions in developing countries, and requests for aid to assist foreign unions. A collection of publications (5780/062 PUBS) consists of printed material either created or collected by the International Relations Department of the ILGWU.
Documentation of the ILGWU's influence and work in international relations is considerable and, though some of it may be found in the most obvious of placesthe David Dubinsky correspondence, the International Relations Department records, or the various editions of Justicesome of it may be found in everyday operational records of local unions and joint boards. These records not only illustrate the work that the ILGWU conducted independently and with the AFL and later the AFL-CIO; they also show the work of individual members and officers working with closely related organizations, such as the Jewish Labor Committee and the Italian-American Labor Council. Additionally, the work of the ILGWU and other unions in the United States is reflected in the records and collected documents of other organizations held at the Kheel Center. These include the papers of Serafino Romualdo, the collected documents of John P. Windmuller, and records of the International Confederation of Free Trade Unions and World Federation of Labor.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5780: ILGWU records 5780/062: ILGWU International Relations Department Records
Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- New York (State); Textile workers -- Labor unions -- New York (State); Clothing trade -- New York (State); Textile industry -- New York (State); Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. International Relations Dept.; Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees
6796102
- Box: 1, Folder: 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: African Communist, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    By The African Communist. no. 100 First Quarter, 1985. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Combatant, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    By PLAN (People's Liberation Army of Namibia). v.9:no.4 (1987:Nov.). Item is in English.
  - Item 3: SWAPO information bulletin, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    By SWAPO. Item is in English.
- Box: 1, Folder: 2, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: Democratic Elections in Namibia, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Democratic Elections In Namibia: An International Experiment in Nation Building, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    By National Democratic Institute For International Affairs. Item is in English.
- Box: 1, Folder: 3, Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: Peace Or Terror: A Crossroads for Southern Africa's Uprooted, Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
    By U.S. Committee For Refugees. Item is in English.
- Box: 1, Folder: 4, Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: Promoting the Process of Democracy in Africa, Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
    By African-American Labor Center, AFL-CIO. Item is in English.
- Box: 1, Folder: 5, Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: Africa Recovery, Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
    By Salim Lone, editor. Item is in English.
- Box: 1, Folder: 6, Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: African Trade Union News, Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
    By Regional Economic Research And Documentation Center. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Labor and Development, Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
    By African-American Labor Center. Item is in English.
- Box: 1, Folder: 7, Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: Self-Reliance In Trade Union Training, Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
    By Tom Mboya Labour College. Item is in English.
- Box: 1, Folder: 8, Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Item 1: Report of the Seminar ITGLWF/FES, Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
    By West African Shoe Industry. Item is in English.
- Box: 1, Folder: 9, Publication (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Item 1: African Unions and Multinational Enterprises, Publication (Box 1, Folder 9)
    By Regional Economic Research and Documentation Center. Item is in English.
- Box: 1, Folder: 10, Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Item 1: The African Worker and the World Economic Crisis, Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
    By International Confederation of Free Trade Unions. Item is in English.
- Box: 1, Folder: 11, Publication (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Item 1: Speak, Publication (Box 1, Folder 11)
    no.58 (1994:Mar.). Item is in English.
- Box: 1, Folder: 12, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Item 1: African-American Labor Center, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12)
    By African-American Labor Center. Flyer. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: African-American Labor Center, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12)
    By African-American Labor Center. Flyer. Copy 2. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: African-American Trade Union Symposium on Employment and Trade, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12)
    By African-American Labor Center. Item is in English; Arabic.
  - Item 4: Centre Afro-Americain Du Travail, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12)
    By African-American Labor Center. Item is in English; French.
  - Item 5: Centre Afro-Americain Du Travail, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12)
    By African-American Labor Center. Item is in French.
  - Item 6: Le Role Du Syndicalisme Dans Le Developpement, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12)
    By J. D. Akume. Item is in French.
- Box: 1, Folder: 13, Publication (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Item 1: Africa: The Potential for Higher Food Production, Publication (Box 1, Folder 13)
    By United States Department of State. Special Report no.125. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Sub-Saharan Africa, Publication (Box 1, Folder 13)
    By United States Department of State. Item is in English.
- Box: 2, Folder: 1, Publication (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: Free Labour World, Publication (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Box: 2, Folder: 2, Publication (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: Trading Away the Future, Publication (Box 2, Folder 2)
    By Pharis J. Harvey & Lauren Riggin. Item is in English.
- Box: 2, Folder: 3, Publication (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: The UCEP/AAFLI Joint Program For Displaced Carpet Children, Publication (Box 2, Folder 3)
    By Underprevileged Children's Education Progreamme, Asian- American Free Labor Institute. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: The UCEP/AAFLI Joint Program For Displaced Carpet Children, Publication (Box 2, Folder 3)
    By Underprevileged Children's Education Progreamme, Asian- American Free Labor Institute. Copy 2. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: The UCEP/AAFLI Joint Program For Displaced Carpet Children, Publication (Box 2, Folder 3)
    By Underprevileged Children's Education Progreamme, Asian- American Free Labor Institute. Copy 3. Item is in English.
- Box: 2, Folder: 4, Publication (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: By The Sweat & Toil of Children, Publication (Box 2, Folder 4)
    By U.S. Department of Labor. Item is in English.
- Box: 2, Folder: 5, Publication (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: Child Labor in the 90's: How Far Have We Come?, Publication (Box 2, Folder 5)
    By Renate Belville, Dorianne Beyer, James G. Godbold, Linda F. Golodner, Bill Goold, Philip J. Landrigan, Barbara C. Lee, Susan H. Pollack. Item is in English.
- Box: 2, Folder: 6, Publication (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: Combating Child Labour, Publication (Box 2, Folder 6)
    By International Labour Office Geneva. Item is in English.
- Box: 2, Folder: 7, Publication (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: Still So Far To Go: Child Labour In The World Today, Publication (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Item 2: Still So Far To Go: Child Labour In The World Today, Publication (Box 2, Folder 7)
    By International Labour Office Geneva. Copy 2. Item is in English.
- Box: 2, Folder: 8, Publication (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Item 1: International Child Labor Problems, Publication (Box 2, Folder 8)
    By U.S. Department of Labor, Bureau of International Labor Affairs. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: International Child Labor Study, Publication (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Box: 2, Folder: 9, Publication (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Item 1: Public Hearings on International Child Labor, Publication (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Box: 2, Folder: 10, Publication (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Item 1: Child Labour: A Briefing Manual, Publication (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Box: 2, Folder: 11, Publication (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Item 1: Children At Work: Peril Or Promise?, Publication (Box 2, Folder 11)
    By Paul F. Cole. Copy 2. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Children At Work: Peril Or Promise?, Publication (Box 2, Folder 11)
    By Paul F. Cole. Copy 3. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Children At Work: Peril Or Promise?, Publication (Box 2, Folder 11)
    By Paul F. Cole. Item is in English.
- Box: 2, Folder: 12, Publication (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Item 1: Campaign Document, Publication (Box 2, Folder 12)
    By International Confederation Of Free Trade Unions. Copy 2. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Campaign Document, Publication (Box 2, Folder 12)
    By International Confederation Of Free Trade Unions. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Child Labour: The World's Best kept Secret, Publication (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Item 4: Child Labour: The World's Best kept Secret, Publication (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Box: 2, Folder: 13, Publication (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Item 1: CLC Launches RUGMARK Consumer Campaign, Publication (Box 2, Folder 13)
    By Child Labor Monitor. Item is in English.
- Box: 3, Folder: 1, Publication (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: Turning Point, Publication (Box 3, Folder 1)
    By Hong Kong Confederation of Trade Unions. February 1991. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Turning Point, Publication (Box 3, Folder 1)
    By Hong Kong Confederation of Trade Unions. October 1993. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Turning Point, Publication (Box 3, Folder 1)
    By Hong Kong Confederation of Trade Unions. June 1994. Item is in English.
- Box: 3, Folder: 2, Publication (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: Development of Taiwan's Textile Industry, Publication (Box 3, Folder 2)
    By Taiwan Textile Federation. Item is in English.
- Box: 3, Folder: 3, Publication (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: China Letter, Publication (Box 3, Folder 3)
    By The Committee for a Free China. November/December 1980. Item is in English.
- Box: 3, Folder: 4, Publication (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: CRS Report for Congress: China After Deng Xiaoping--Implications for the United States, Publication (Box 3, Folder 4)
    By Robert G. Sutter. April 7, 1995. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Policy Impact Panel on the Future of U.S.-China Relations, Publication (Box 3, Folder 4)
    By Policy Impact Panel. May 11, 1994; co chaired by The Honorable Henry A. Kissinger and The Honorable Cyrus R. Vance. Item is in English.
- Box: 3, Folder: 5, Publication (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: Memorandum to the Governments of Hong Kong and the United Kingdom Regarding the Protection of Vietnamese Asylum, Publication (Box 3, Folder 5)
    By Amnesty International. January 1990. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: People's Republic of China: Preliminary Findings on Killings of Unarmed Civilians. Arbitrary Arrests and Summary Executions, Publication (Box 3, Folder 5)
    By Amnesty International. August 1989. Item is in English.
- Box: 3, Folder: 6, Publication (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: Darkness Before Dawn: Massacre at Tiananmen!, Publication (Box 3, Folder 6)
    By Asian Students Association and Hong Kong Federation of Students. June 1989. Cover only in English and Chinese. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Echoes from Tiananmen, Publication (Box 3, Folder 6)
    By Friends of Chinese Minzhu. no.5 (1991:Mar.). Cover only in English and Chinese. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Echose from Tiananmen, Publication (Box 3, Folder 6)
    By Friends of Chinese Minzhu. no.1 (1989:June 15). Cover only in English and Chinese. Photocopy. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: Echose from Tiananment, Publication (Box 3, Folder 6)
    By Friends of Chinese Minzhu. no.1 (1989:June 15). Cover only in English and Chinese. Item is in English.
  - Item 5: Testimonial to History tiananmen Square 1989.4.15-6.4, Publication (Box 3, Folder 6)
    By HK Alliance in Support of Patriotic Democratic Movements of China. Item is in English; Chinese.
  - Item 6: Testimonial to History Tiananmen Square 1989.4.15-6.4, Publication (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Box: 3, Folder: 7, Publication (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: [Title in Chinese] 88-89, Publication (Box 3, Folder 7)
    Text is entirely in Chinese. Item is in Chinese.
  - Item 2: [Title in Chinese] 88-89, Publication (Box 3, Folder 7)
    Text is entirely in Chinese. Copy 2. Item is in Chinese.
- Box: 3, Folder: 8, Publication (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Item 1: Continuing Religious Repression in China, Publication (Box 3, Folder 8)
    By Asia Watch. June 1993. Item is in English.
- Box: 3, Folder: 9, Publication (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Item 1: China Labour Bulletin, Publication (Box 3, Folder 9)
    By China Labour Bulletin. Issue No. 9 & 10 - December 1994. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: China Labour Bulletin, Publication (Box 3, Folder 9)
    By China Labour Bulletin. Issue No. 8 - October 1994. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: China Labour Bulletin, Publication (Box 3, Folder 9)
    By China Labour Bulletin. Issue No. 7 - September 1994. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: China Labour Bulletin, Publication (Box 3, Folder 9)
    By China Labour Bulletin. Issue No. 6 - August 1994. Item is in English.
  - Item 5: China Labour Bulletin, Publication (Box 3, Folder 9)
    By China Labour Bulletin. Issue No. 5 - July 1994. Item is in English.
  - Item 6: China Labour Bulletin, Publication (Box 3, Folder 9)
    By China Labour Bulletin. Issue No. 4 - July 1994; month crossed out and JUN 1994 stamped. Item is in English.
  - Item 7: China Labour Bulletin, Publication (Box 3, Folder 9)
    By China Labour Bulletin. Issue No. 3 - May 1994. Item is in English.
  - Item 8: China Labour Bulletin, Publication (Box 3, Folder 9)
    By China Labour Bulletin. Issue No. 2 - April 1994. Item is in English.
  - Item 9: China Labour Bulletin, Publication (Box 3, Folder 9)
    By China Labour Bulletin. Issue No. 1 - March 1994. Item is in English.
  - Item 10: China Labour Bulletin, Publication (Box 3, Folder 9)
    By China Labour Bulletin. Issue No. 15 June 1995. Item is in English.
  - Item 11: China Labour Bulletin, Publication (Box 3, Folder 9)
    By China Labour Bulletin. Issue No. 14 - May 1995. Item is in English.
  - Item 12: China Labour Bulletin, Publication (Box 3, Folder 9)
    By China Labour Bulletin. Issue No. 13 - April 1995. Item is in English.
  - Item 13: China Labour Bulletin, Publication (Box 3, Folder 9)
    By China Labour Bulletin. Issue No. 12 - March 1995. Item is in English.
  - Item 14: China Labour Bulletin, Publication (Box 3, Folder 9)
    By China Labour Bulletin. Issue No. 12 - March 1995; photocopy. Item is in English.
  - Item 15: China Labour Bulletin, Publication (Box 3, Folder 9)
    By China Labour Bulletin. Issue No. 11 - February 1995. Item is in English.
- Box: 3, Folder: 10, Publication (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Item 1: China Labor Newletter, Publication (Box 3, Folder 10)
    By Asian-American Free Labor Institute. Vol. 1 No. 1. Item is in Chinese.
  - Item 2: China Labor Newletter, Publication (Box 3, Folder 10)
    By Asian-American Free Labor Institute. Vol. 1 No. 2. Item is in Chinese.
  - Item 3: China Labor Newletter, Publication (Box 3, Folder 10)
    By Asian-American Free Labor Institute. Vol. 1 No. 3. Item is in Chinese.
  - Item 4: China Labor Newletter, Publication (Box 3, Folder 10)
    By Asian-American Free Labor Institute. Vol. 1 No. 4. Item is in Chinese.
  - Item 5: China Labor Newletter, Publication (Box 3, Folder 10)
    By Asian-American Free Labor Institute. Vol. 2 No 2. Item is in Chinese.
  - Item 6: China Labor Newletter, Publication (Box 3, Folder 10)
    By Asian-American Free Labor Institute. Vol. 2 No. 3. Item is in Chinese.
  - Item 7: China Labor Newletter, Publication (Box 3, Folder 10)
    By Asian-American Free Labor Institute. Vol. 2 No. 4. Item is in Chinese.
  - Item 8: China Labor Newletter, Publication (Box 3, Folder 10)
    By Asian-American Free Labor Institute. Vol. 2 No. 6. Item is in Chinese.
- Box: 3, Folder: 11, Publication (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Item 1: China Labor Market, Publication (Box 3, Folder 11)
    By Asian- American Free Labor Institute. Vol. 3 No. 10, October 1992. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: China Labor Notes, Publication (Box 3, Folder 11)
    By Asian- American Free Labor Institute. Issue No. 10, November 1990. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: China Labor Notes, Publication (Box 3, Folder 11)
    By Asian- American Free Labor Institute. Issue No. 9, October 1990. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: China Labor Notes, Publication (Box 3, Folder 11)
    By Asian- American Free Labor Institute. Issue No. 8, Special Hong Kong Issue, September 1990. Item is in English.
  - Item 5: China Labor Notes, Publication (Box 3, Folder 11)
    By Asian- American Free Labor Institute. Issue No. 7, August 1990. Item is in English.
  - Item 6: China Labor Notes, Publication (Box 3, Folder 11)
    By Asian- American Free Labor Institute. Issue No. 6, July 1990. Item is in English.
  - Item 7: China Labor Notes, Publication (Box 3, Folder 11)
    By Asian- American Free Labor Institute. Issue No. 5, June 1990. Item is in English.
  - Item 8: China Labor Notes, Publication (Box 3, Folder 11)
    By Asian- American Free Labor Institute. Issue No.4, May 1990. Item is in English.
  - Item 9: China Labor Notes, Publication (Box 3, Folder 11)
    By Asian- American Free Labor Institute. Issue No.3, April 1990. Item is in English.
  - Item 10: China Labor Notes, Publication (Box 3, Folder 11)
    By Asian- American Free Labor Institute. Issue No.2, March 1990. Item is in English.
  - Item 11: China Labor Notes, Publication (Box 3, Folder 11)
    By Asian- American Free Labor Institute. Issue No. 1, February 1990. Item is in English.
  - Item 12: China Labor Notes, Publication (Box 3, Folder 11)
    By Asian- American Free Labor Institute. Vol. 2 No. 12, December 1991. Item is in English.
  - Item 13: China Labor Notes, Publication (Box 3, Folder 11)
    By Asian- American Free Labor Institute. Vol. 2 No. 11, November 1991. Item is in English.
  - Item 14: China Labor Notes, Publication (Box 3, Folder 11)
    By Asian- American Free Labor Institute. Vo. 2 No.10, October 1991. Item is in English.
  - Item 15: China Labor Notes, Publication (Box 3, Folder 11)
    By Asian- American Free Labor Institute. Vo. 2 No.9. Item is in English.
  - Item 16: China Labor Notes, Publication (Box 3, Folder 11)
    By Asian- American Free Labor Institute. Vo.2 No. 8. Item is in English.
  - Item 17: China Labor Notes, Publication (Box 3, Folder 11)
    By Asian- American Free Labor Institute. Vo.2 No.7, July 1991. Item is in English.
  - Item 18: China Labor Notes, Publication (Box 3, Folder 11)
    By Asian- American Free Labor Institute. Vo. 2 No. 6, June 1991. Item is in English.
  - Item 19: China Labor Notes, Publication (Box 3, Folder 11)
    By Asian- American Free Labor Institute. Vo.2 No.5, May 1991. Item is in English.
  - Item 20: China Labor Notes, Publication (Box 3, Folder 11)
    By Asian- American Free Labor Institute. Vo. 2 No.4, April 1991. Item is in English.
  - Item 21: China Labor Notes, Publication (Box 3, Folder 11)
    By Asian- American Free Labor Institute. Item is in English.
  - Item 22: China Labor Notes, Publication (Box 3, Folder 11)
    By Asian- American Free Labor Institute. Vo. 2 No 2, February 1991. Item is in English.
  - Item 23: China Labor Notes, Publication (Box 3, Folder 11)
    By Asian- American Free Labor Institute. Vo 2 No.1, January 1991. Item is in English.
  - Item 24: China Labor Notes, Publication (Box 3, Folder 11)
    By Asian- American Free Labor Institute. Vol.3 No. 12, December 1992. Item is in English.
  - Item 25: China Labor Notes, Publication (Box 3, Folder 11)